webinspector.com 2018-04-28

# Policies and Practices of the Comodo Companies

This privacy policy describes the policies and practices of the different Comodo companies, including Comodo Group, Inc., Comodo Security Solutions, Inc., and DNS.COM, LLC (collectively and individually referred to herein as "Comodo"), in collecting, using, and safeguarding the private information that may be obtained through use of each company's products, services and websites. Questions about this privacy policy may be submitted by an email to [privacy@comodo.com](mailto:privacy@comodo.com). This privacy policy applies to each of the Comodo entities, but not to Comodo's partners or affiliates, which may have separate privacy policies.

**Information Collection**

Personal information is collected from customers only after obtaining consent, which is obtained when customers are prompted for information when subscribing to the services, by using a Comodo website, downloading a product, or requesting further information. Personally-identifiable information is not collected when a user simply browses the website. Comodo may contact customers about offers and opportunities from Comodo or its business partners, to conduct surveys, and gather feedback. This privacy statement does not extend to any information that is beyond the control of Comodo.

If you are located in California, IP addresses are considered personally identifiable information

In the event that third party features and functionalities are incorporated in or made available in or through Comodo products, then the policies of those third parties apply.  Please visit each third party’s license agreement and privacy policy to better understand their terms of use and data collection practices.

For Comodo Security Solutions, Inc. products and services, additional information collection is described in the policy at CSS Information Collection.

**Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act Statement**

Comodo sites, products and services are not directed to children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personally identifying information, we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

**Services**

Enrolling in Comodo's subscription service may require a customer to provide certain personal information and enter into a Subscriber Agreement. Nothing herein is intended to modify the terms in the Subscriber Agreement.

**Product Download**

Downloading a product will often require the input of personal information. This information will be used by Comodo or its affiliates to contact the customer about Comodo's products and services, including product updates and associated promotional material. This information may also be used as collated general demographic information to improve Comodo's products and services.

**Cookies**

A cookie is a piece of data stored on a computer's hard disk containing information about the owner. Comodo may employ the use of cookies for measuring the success of advertising and affiliate network membership. Our partners may use cookies. Comodo does not exercise any access or control of such cookies.

Comodo's websites use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"), to evaluate the use of the Comodo site. Google Analytics places a third party cookie on your computer that is then used to compile reports of visitor traffic and internet usage. Google analytics does not have a database of individual profiles for each visitor and only collects aggregate data.

**Re-Targeting**

Comodo permits the operation of a retargeting consumer marketing program, including, but not limited to, the provision of anonymous consumer information to a third-party provider of such a program. A link to the Network Advertising Initiative’s consumer opt-out page is located at [www.networkadvertising](http://www.networkadvertising.com/) .org/managing/opt_out.asp and allows the consumer to opt-out of such retargeting programs.

**Log Files**

Comodo uses log files comprising of non-personally identifiable information to analyze trends, administer the site, track movements throughout the site, calculate the number of document and file downloads, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

**Sharing**

Comodo will share aggregated demographic and other information with our partners and affiliates. Information provided to Comodo will be protected by Comodo and not sold or rented to any unrelated third parties without the express consent of the information provider, except that Comodo may disclose data to its affiliates and business partners who have established similar privacy standards, when legally obligated to do so, or if disclosure is required to protect the rights over Comodo, Comodo's customers, or the users of Comodo's services. Comodo may also share aggregate demographic data that does not contain any personally identifiable information.

**External Links**

The Comodo website contains links to external websites which are outside the scope of this privacy statement. Comodo is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites and does not control the accuracy of information displayed by such websites.

**Forums, Bulletin Boards, Testimonials, Chat Rooms, and Surveys**

Personal information submitted through a forum, bulletin board, testimonial, or chat room operated by Comodo may be collected, used, and read by third parties, including other users. Comodo is not responsible for any information submitted through these services. We occasionally request information from customers via surveys. Participation in these customer surveys is voluntary. Survey information is used to improve this web site and our services and products.

**Refer a Friend Program**

Comodo provides the ability to send emails to your email contacts. You can use the Refer a Friend page to log into your mail account and send a message to your friends. This message may be customized by you. Comodo does not store any of the information entered by you as part of the email process.

**Security**

Comodo protects information both online and off-line. The transmission of information, including any payment information, is encrypted and protected using [Secure Sockets Layer (SSL)](http://www.instantssl.com/). Stored customer information is kept in a secure environment where access is restricted to employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example billing administration or the development team). Employees are required to use password-protected screen-savers and keep their computers up-to-date.

**Permissions**

With your express permission, certain Comodo applications, such as Comodo Mobile Security and Comodo Anti-Theft, allow the applications access to Global Positioning Data (GPS), cellular network, Google analytics or other similar data. When requested by you, these applications also specifically access, modify and delete personal data and may send emails or messages from your device. Please review the EULA for each application or product and the associated Permissions to obtain further details for a particular application.

**Choice / Opt out**

Customers may occasionally receive information on products, services, and special deals from Comodo or may receive informational newsletters. Customers are given the opportunity to 'opt-out' of having information used for purposes not directly related to the Comodo service at the point where the information is requested. Customers may also elect not to receive additional promotional communications using the opt-out link provided in each promotional email or by emailing [optout@comodo.com](mailto:optout@comodo.com). Customers may not opt-out of receiving service announcement updates as they contain important security information about the services.

**Amendments to this Privacy Policy**

Comodo reserves the right to amend this privacy policy at any time. Any amendment will be made by posting the changes to the website. Customers must check the website periodically to be aware of any changes to the privacy statement. Your continued use of the website or Comodo product or service constitutes your acceptance of those changes.
